# Hugo Arriojas

Front-End Web Developer

(647)-339-3480 hugo.arriojas@hotmail.com Ottawa,ON

HugoA.dev Github.com/HugoArriojas Linkedin.com/in/HugoArriojas

## PROFILE

I am a web developer, accounting administrator, and marine biologist with experience in data analytics, accounting, and customer service roles.

I enjoy applying my skills in order to create responsive and user-friendly apps in React and Javascript.

With my experience in project management and strong presentation skills, I aim to bring our design to life while still maintaining a focus on accessibility.

## **SKILLS**

## Web Development

HTML

- RESTful APIs
- Firebase
- CSS SCSS
- Git collaboration
- React
- Version Control
- Figma
- Project Scope
  - Management

#### **Accounting**

- Excel
- **ERP Experience**
- GAAP
  - Full-cycle
- AR & AP

#### **Data Analytics**

- R / RStudio
- MATLAB
- ANVIO

#### Design

- Photoshop
- Lightroom
- Premiere Pro

# LANGUAGES

**English** - Fluent Spanish - Fluent French - Basic

### **EDUCATION**

September 2021 to December 2021 Juno College of Technology Web Development Immersive Bootcamp & Javascript Course

# **Dalhousie University**

September 2013 to April 2017

Honours Bachelor of Science in Marine Biology & Statistics

## **PROJECTS**

#### **Reactive Retail**

Git, React, SASS, HTML, CSS, Firebase, Figma

Reactive Retail is a mock retail site built entirely in React using the Fake-Store API. In the app, users are able to filter through a variety of products via category, add items to their Firebase cart, and then convert product prices to different currencies.

Live Link: bit.ly/ReactiveRetail Git Repo: bit.ly/ReactiveRetailGit

#### The Not So Social Planner

Git, React, Firebase, HTML, CSS, Figma

This React group project works as a social planner wherein users are able to submit recurring weekly events into a calendar. Should the user choose to not go through with their social commitments, they are able to check out what shows are streaming at the time. This project simulates an agency-style environment, the project scope being outlined in a client brief.

**Live Link:** bit.ly/NotSocialPlanner Git Repo: bit.ly/NotSocialPlannerGit

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Accounting Administrator**

March 2019 to July 2021

Carson Auto Group, Victoria Ford Alliance

- Reviewed and reconciled banking, warranty, and inventory accounts using CDK software, taking care of hundreds of clients spanning 5 large car dealerships.
- Worked with a team to maintain a large database of records using a variety of accounting software in order to track deals, payments, and inventory.
- Spearheaded several projects to increase efficiency in the workplace and aimed to create a standardized method for future workers that may hold the role.

#### **At-Sea Fisheries Observer**

January 2018 to November 2018

Archipelago Marine Research

- Gathered, verified, audited, and reported biological and commercial catch data for the Department of Fisheries and Oceans while working in extreme environments.
- Produced detailed & adaptive cruise reports and program summaries while living onboard foreign vessels for extended periods of time.